import { Quiz } from '../../types';

const IdentifiersTranslationQuiz: Quiz[] = [
  {
    description: 'Opakujte v angličtině',
    name: 'Identifikátory - překlady',
    questions: [
      {
        answer: ['mister', 'mr'],
        question: 'pán'
      },
      {
        answer: ['man'],
        question: 'muž'
      },
      {
        answer: ['chairman', 'sinatra'],
        question: 'předseda'
      },
      {
        answer: ['judge'],
        question: 'soudce'
      },
      {
        answer: ['castle'],
        question: 'hrad'
      },
      {
        answer: ['machine'],
        question: 'stroj'
      },
      {
        answer: ['woman'],
        question: 'žena'
      },
      {
        answer: ['rose'],
        question: 'růže'
      },
      {
        answer: ['song', 'tune'],
        question: 'píseň'
      },
      {
        answer: ['bone'],
        question: 'kost'
      },
      {
        answer: ['city'],
        question: 'město'
      },
      {
        answer: ['sea', 'ocean'],
        question: 'moře'
      },
      {
        answer: ['chicken'],
        question: 'kuře'
      },
      {
        answer: ['building'],
        question: 'stavení'
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    description: 'Určete pohlaví (N - střední, F - ženský, M - mužský životný, I - mužský neživotný)',
    name: 'Identifikátory - rod',
    questions: [
      {
        answer: ['m'],
        question: 'pán'
      },
      {
        answer: ['m'],
        question: 'muž'
      },
      {
        answer: ['m'],
        question: 'předseda'
      },
      {
        answer: ['m'],
        question: 'soudce'
      },
      {
        answer: ['i'],
        question: 'hrad'
      },
      {
        answer: ['i'],
        question: 'stroj'
      },
      {
        answer: ['f'],
        question: 'žena'
      },
      {
        answer: ['f'],
        question: 'růže'
      },
      {
        answer: ['f'],
        question: 'píseň'
      },
      {
        answer: ['f'],
        question: 'kost'
      },
      {
        answer: ['n'],
        question: 'město'
      },
      {
        answer: ['n'],
        question: 'moře'
      },
      {
        answer: ['n'],
        question: 'kuře'
      },
      {
        answer: ['n'],
        question: 'stavení'
      }
    ]
  }
];

export default IdentifiersTranslationQuiz;
